Finding Aid for University of Michigan. Office of the Registrar Records 1840-2003
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Topical Files 1924-1994
  - Numbering System circa 1960 (student) (Box 17)
  - Office Procedures 1963-1967 (Box 17)
  - Orientation Office 1964-1966 (Box 17)
  - Palmquist Studies 1940 (Box 17)
  - Preclassification of Students
    - 1963 (Box 17)
    - 1967 (Box 17)
  - Records Office 1966-1967 (Box 17)
  - Registration
    - General
      - 1966-1967 (Box 17)
      - 1969-1977 (Box 17)
    - Advanced 1958-1961 (Box 17)
    - Cards and Procedures 1959-1969 (Box 17)
    - Early
      - 1962 (Box 17)
      - 1968/69 (Box 17)
    - Goals 1969 (Box 17)
    - Medical School/Inteflex Procedures 1960-1986 (Box 17)
    - Permits 1975-1977 (Box 17)
    - Procedures
      - 1958 (Box 17)
      - 1961 (Box 17)
      - 1972-1978 (Box 17)
  - Registration and Records Conversion, 1964/5 (Box 17)
  - Report Study 1959 (re:enrollment) (Box 17)
  - Graduate Hold Procedure 1968-1978 (Box 18)
  - Graduate Program Guidelines 1976-1977 (Box 18)
  - Graduate Records Study 1940 (Box 18)
  - Graduate School
    - IBM Card Codes circa 1959 (Box 18)
    - Reporting Procedures 1947 (Box 18)
    - Graduate School/Registrar Meeting Minutes 1974-1977 (Box 18)
  - Handbooks
    - Information Retrieval Systems Handbook, 1984 (Box 18)
    - Student Database Terminal Handbook, 1973 (Box 18)
    - University Course Data Base Handbook, 1979 (Box 18)
  - Hold Credit Procedure 1959 (Box 18)
  - Housing Reports 1966 (Box 18)
  - Housing Survey 1959 (Box 18)
  - LS&A Policies 1974-1977 (Box 18)
  - LS&A/Registrar Meetings 1973-1977 (Box 18)
  - Michigan Junior College Study 1959 (Box 18)
  - North Central Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools 1927-1937 (Box 18)
  - Numbering System circa 1960 (student) (Box 18)
  - Office Procedures 1963-1967 (Box 18)
  - Orientation Office 1964-1966 (Box 18)
  - Palmquist Studies 1940 (Box 18)
  - Preclassification of Students
    - 1963 (Box 18)
    - 1967 (Box 18)
  - Records Office 1966-1967 (Box 18)
  - Registration
    - General
      - 1966-1967 (Box 18)
      - 1969-1977 (Box 18)
    - Advanced 1958-1961 (Box 18)
    - Cards and Procedures 1959-1969 (Box 18)
    - Early
      - 1962 (Box 18)
      - 1968/69 (Box 18)
    - Goals 1969 (Box 18)
    - Medical School/Inteflex Procedures 1960-1986 (Box 18)
    - Permits 1975-1977 (Box 18)
    - Procedures
      - 1961 (Box 18)
      - 1972-1978 (Box 18)
  - Registration and Records Conversion, 1964/5 (Box 18)
  - Report Study 1959 (Box 18)
    (re:enrollment)
  - Reports
    - Academic Records of 522 Veterans Who Entered the University as Special Admission Cases, 1949 (Box 19)
    - Commission on Year-Round Integrated Operation, 1961 (Box 19)
    - Demographic Study of Student Record System, 1964 (Box 19)
    - MRC-CUMREC, A Historical Review, circa 1983 (Box 19)
    - An On-Line Terminal Registration Supported by a Data Base Environment, circa 1976 (Box 19)
    - A Report on Automated Class Selection, 1957 (Box 19)
    - Report of Special Committee on Central Office of Admissions, 1930 (Box 19)
    - Student Characteristics Data Base Batch Maintenance General Systems Design Specification, 1976 (Box 19)
    - Student Data Base File-A Proposal to Change, 1984 (Box 19)
    - Study of Academic Progress of Transfer Students, 1954 (Box 19)
    - A Study of Freshman Failures, 1930 (Box 19)
    - A Study of the Student Address and Information Systems at the University of Michigan, 1971 (Box 19)
  - Scheduling Office
    - General 1955-1983 (Box 19)
    - College Resources Analysis System (CRAS) 1969-1972 (Box 19)
    - Historical Materials 1967-1974 (Box 19)
  - Selective Service 1966-1967 (Box 19)
  - Senior Staff Meetings 1993-1994 (Box 19)
  - Staff Meetings, 1966/7 (Box 19)
  - Statistical Services-Reports Services Codes 1961 (Box 19)
  - Student Affairs Systems Committee 1960 (Box 19)
  - Student Database circa 1963 (Box 19)
  - Student Database Items 1968-1970 (Box 19)
  - Student Fees, Committee on 1972-1977 (Box 19)
  - Student Number Criteria 1976 (Box 19)
  - Student Ranking 1958/59 (Box 19)
    (by class and school)
  - Student Records and their Use, Committee on 1967 (Box 19)
  - Subgroup Chairs 1988 (Box 19)
  - Systems and Procedures Committee 1959-1961 (minutes) (Box 19)
  - Tabulating Service 1948-1956 (Box 19)
  - Tape Conversion 1963 (Box 19)
  - Veteran Survey 1946 (Box 19)
  - Veterans, List of 1945 (Box 19)
  - Withdrawal Notice undated (Box 19)
- Academic Record Project 1987-1994
  The Academic Record Project (ARP) series (5 linear feet) documents the computerization of the academic record. The records, compiled by Patricia V. Lehman, a member of various project committees, include information on the Planning Committee for Computerization of the Academic Record (PCCAR), the Student Characteristics Data Base (SCDB), the Michigan Audit Reporting System (MARS), and the Admissions System Production Group Committee (ASP).
  The Academic Record Project, which began in 1987, was designed to minimize the duplication of work by record keepers and to maximize accessibility of student record information by way of a cooperatively maintained electronic resource between the Office of the Registrar and the schools and colleges. The SCDB is an assemblage of hierarchical databases, flat files and hard copy that comprised the student information data resources. It was the SCDB Task Team that devised a plan to: determine the functional requirements of the fully computerized academic record; add data elements in appropriate logical segments to the SCDB to serve the functional requirements revealed by the investigation; and develop transactions, screens, and reporting capabilities needed to deliver the required services.
  - General 1990 (Box 20)
  - Academic Audit
    - General 1988/89 (Box 20)
    - Condition Codes 1990-1993 (Box 20)
    - Detail Design Documentation 1991 (Box 20)
    - Pre-Pilot/Pilot
      - General 1991-1992 (Box 20)
      - Minutes 1991-1992 (Box 20)
      - Test Data 1991 (Box 20)
      - Study 1989-1990 (Box 20)
    - Progress Reports 1980-1992 (Box 20)
    - Research Team
      - 1989/90 (Box 20)
      - 1990/91 (Box 20)
  - Academic Record Management Team (ARM) 1990-1993 (Box 20)
  - Academic Record Training Group 1990-1991 (Box 20)
  - Access Group 1990-1991 (Box 20)
  - Access to Student Data 1992/93 (Box 20)
  - Admissions System Production Group Committee (ASP)
    - General
      - 1987-1988 (Box 20)
      - 1989 (Box 20)
    - Minutes
      - 1987 (Box 20)
      - 1988 (Box 20)
      - 1989 (Box 20)
      - 1990 (Box 20)
      - 1991, 2 folders (Box 20)
      - 1992 (Box 20)
      - 1993 (Box 20)
    - Workshop 1993 (Box 20)
  - Admissions Task Team 1987-1991 (Box 20)
  - Audit Implementation Committee 1992-1993 (re:engineering) (Box 20)
  - Audit, Rackham Pilot 1989-1992 (Box 20)
  - Budget Priorities Committee (BPC),1991 (pilo project on graduate admissions data) (Box 21)
  - CLARENCE 1993/94 (Academic Record Project/Registrar Office implementation group) (Box 21)
  - Committee Participants 1987-1988 (Box 21)
  - Comprehensive Studies Program Information System 1990 (Box 21)
  - Cumulative to Term Totals Project 1992-1993 (Box 21)
  - Data Modelling 1990-1993 (Box 21)
  - Degree Audit Reporting System (DARS) 1989 (correspondence) (Box 21)
  - Degree/Certificate Subgroup 1989 (Box 21)
  - Degree Tables 1991 (Box 21)
  - Detail Design Document, Reactions to 1990 (Box 21)
  - Documentation Coordination Group 1990 (Box 21)
  - Field of Study Consistency 1992-1994 (Box 21)
  - Future Implementation 1992/93 (Box 21)
  - Glossary undated (Box 21)
  - Goals/History undated (Box 21)
  - Guide to the On-line Academic Record Information, 1993 (draft) (Box 21)
  - Image 1991 (minutes) (Box 21)
  - Implementation in Engineering (IMP)
    - General 1992, 2 folders (Box 21)
    - Minutes 1992/93 (Box 21)
    - Plans and Time Lines 1992-1993 (Box 21)
  - Information Systems and Services 1990-1992 (updates) (Box 21)
  - Interface 1991-1992 (Box 21)
  - Information, Technology, and Design (ITD)/Registrar Office Meetings 1993/94 (Box 21)
  - Management Team 1993 (Box 21)
  - Michigan Audit Reporting System (MARS)
    - Academic Audit 1988 (sample) (Box 21)
    - Documentation Drafts 1988-1991 (Box 21)
    - MARS/DARS (Degree Audit Reporting System) Documentation 1991-1993 (Box 21)
    - Maintain Program 1990-1991 (Box 21)
    - Requirement Text 1990-1991 (Box 21)
    - Users Groups 1992 (Box 21)
  - Multiple Degrees 1987-1990 (Box 21)
  - New Grade System 1988 (Box 21)
  - On-line Academic Record Information, Guide to, 1990-1991 (Box 21)
  - On-Line Previous Experience and Transfer Credit Transfer Subsystems 1993 (Box 21)
  - Optical Disk Imaging System 1992 (proposal) (Box 21)
  - Participant Lists 1993 (Box 22)
  - Phase One Overview 1990 (Box 22)
  - Planning Committee for the Computerization of the Academic Record (PCCAR)
    - General
      - 1987-1988 (Box 22)
      - 1988-1992 (includes minutes) (Box 22)
    - Funding 1988-1990 (Box 22)
    - Minutes 1988-1992 (Box 22)
    - Reorganization 1992 (Box 22)
    - Survey of Needs Workshop 1987 (Box 22)
  - Presentation 1991 (for Provost) (Box 22)
  - Reports
    - Academic Record Project: Academic Record System B Tester Training Roles and Responsibilities, 1991 (Box 22)
    - Computerized Academic Record Documentation Report, 1990 (Box 22)
    - Computerized Academic Record Training Report,, 1990 (Box 22)
    - Cumulative to Term Totals System description Document,, 1994 (draft) (Box 22)
    - Progress Report: Committee for Planning the Computerized Academic Record, 1986 (Box 22)
    - Test Coordination Group-Report to the Student Characteristics Data Base Task Team, 1990 (Box 22)
  - Reorganization 1992-1993 (Box 22)
  - Requirements 1991 (Box 22)
  - Scholarship/Fellowship 1992 (Box 22)
  - Sequence Table 1990-1993 (Box 22)
  - Status Reports 1990 (Box 22)
  - Strategic Data Planning 1993-1994 (Box 22)
  - Student Accounting Project
    - 1990-1991 (Box 22)
    - 1992/93 (Box 22)
  - Student Accounting System-Phase 1 1992 (Box 22)
  - Student Characteristics Data Base (SCDB)
    - Academic Report 1988-1992 (Box 22)
    - Admissions Interface 1991-1992 (Box 22)
    - Audit Subgroup 1988-1990 (Box 22)
    - Course Tables Subgroup 1988-1990 (Box 22)
    - Data Element Standing Committee 1989-1990 (minutes) (Box 22)
    - Degree/Certificate Subgroup-minutes 1988-1989 (Box 22)
    - Essential Data Elements 1993 (Box 22)
    - Interface Group Committee
      - General 1985-1992 (Box 22)
      - Minutes
        - 1985 (Box 22)
        - 1991/92 (Box 22)
    - Minutes
      - 1986-1988 (Box 22)
      - 1989-1990 (Box 22)
      - 1991 (Box 22)
      - 1992 (Box 23)
      - 1993 (Box 23)
    - Modelling Group 1990 (Box 23)
    - Open Items 1990-1991 (Box 23)
    - Presentation 1987 (Box 23)
    - Previous Experience Subgroup (Prex)
      - Minutes 1988-1989 (Box 23)
      - Previous Experience Document 1988 (Box 23)
      - Subgroup 1988-1989 (Box 23)
    - Problems/Issues 1989-1992, 2 folders (Box 23)
    - Reconfiguration 1990-1991 (Box 23)
    - Report of Phase 1 1987 (Box 23)
    - Subgroup Monthly Reports 1989 (Box 23)
    - Task List 1988 (Box 23)
    - Task Team
      - General (includes some minutes)
        - 1987-1989 (Box 23)
        - 1990-1991 (Box 23)
        - 1992 (Box 23)
      - Academic Record Testing 1989/90 (Box 23)
      - Data Entry 1991 (Box 23)
      - Minutes 1992 (Box 23)
      - Planning 1990/91 (Box 23)
      - Purpose/Member List 1988-1992 (Box 23)
      - SDDT 1990-1992 (Box 24)
      - Training Group 1988-1990 (Box 24)
      - Transcripts 1991-1992 (Box 24)
      - Upgrade Group 1990 (Box 24)
  - Student Profile Data Guide 1987 (Box 24)
  - Subgroup Detail System Design 1989 (Box 24)
  - System Development and Design Team 1992/93 (Box 24)
  - System Testing 1990/91 (Box 24)
  - Test Coordination Group 1993 (Box 24)
  - Training Coordination Group 1990 (Box 24)
  - Transcript
    - 1991 (Box 24)
    - 1993 (Box 24)
  - Transcript Task Team 1987 (Box 24)
  - Transfer Credit 1987-1992 (Box 24)
  - Unit Reps meetings 1991 (Box 24)
  - Users' Group for On-line Systems (UGFOS) 1987-1992 (minutes) (Box 24)
- Reports and Statistics 1840-2003
  The Reports and Statistics, 1840-2003 series (1 linear foot) is comprised of statistics and reports generated by the University of Michigan Office of the Registrar during the years 1840 to 2003, with the bulk years being 1960 to 1980. The statistics, some of which were produced for publications and others for office use only, yield and analyze data on the student population. The data is organized into various reference points including: academic term, gender, nationality, geographic area, class level, grade point average, and academic unit. The series is divided into two subseries; Enrollment Statistics, which focuses on student body data, and Grade Point Average, which analyzes average grades of the student population.
  - Enrollment Statistics
    - Home Cases and Warnings, 1926-30, 1961-62
      [SR RESTRICTED until July 1 2036; removed to vault]
    - Long-range Statistics 1840-2003 (Box 25)
    - 1900-1929 (Box 25)
    - 1930-1939 (Box 25)
    - 1940-1944 (Box 25)
    - 1945-1949 (Box 25)
    - 1950-1954 (Box 25)
    - 1955-1959 (Box 25)
    - 1960 (Box 25)
    - 1961 (Box 25)
    - 1962-1963 (Box 25)
    - 1964 (Box 25)
    - 1965 (Box 25)
    - 1966 (Box 25)
    - 1967 (Box 25)
    - 1968 (Box 25)
    - 1969 (Box 25)
    - 1970-1974 (Box 25)
    - 1975-1979 (Box 25)
    - 1980-1989 (Box 25)
  - Grade Point Average Statistics
    - 1912-1913, 1924-1934 (Box 25)
    - 1930-1939 (Box 25)
    - 1940-43 1945-1949 (Box 25)
    - 1950-52 1956-1958 (Box 25)
    - 1960-61 1963-1965 (Box 25)
    - 1970-1979 (Box 25)
    - 1980-1985 (Box 25)
Related Material
For additional information regarding the Office of the Registrar, researchers should consult:
University of Michigan. Office of the Registrar. Publications
University of Michigan. Bureau of School Services record group
University of Michigan President Reports
Ira M. Smith papers
The University of Michigan an Encyclopedic Survey, Wilfred B. Shaw, editor (Ann Arbor; University of Michigan Press, 1942)